Claudio Corsi

(h) 781.270.5593 | (c) 617.515.5490 | clcorsi@yahoo.com | $\underline{\text{LinkedIn Profile}} \mid \underline{\text{GitHub Profile}} \mid \text{ReplIt Profile}$

Profile

Seasoned Software Engineer with 25+ years of experience developing complex server-side and client-side software products from design through implementation using mainly Java and C/C++. Experienced in all other aspects of the software development process including scheduling, maintaining, presenting, mentoring, debugging and documenting.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, C/C++, C#, Python, Groovy, Perl, Ruby, JavaScript

Frameworks: Mockito, PowerMock, JUnit, BCEL, ASM, Camel, RMI, JNDI, JDBC, JAXP, XML, XSLT, DOM, SAX,

JNI, EJB, Servlet, JSP, JTA, JMS, JMX

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Netbeans, IntelliJ, Emacs, XCode, Mercurial, Subversion, Ant,

make, maven

Application Servers: Weblogic Server, WebSphere Application Server, Tomcat, JBoss AS, ActiveMQ

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD DBMS: Oracle DBMS, MySQL, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Office Tools: Microsoft Office, Google Office Suite

Experience

Member of the Technical Staff

2012 - 2020

Riverbed Technology/Aternity LLC

Cambridge, MA

- Part of the team that implements and maintains the Java and .NET{CORE} instrumentation agents
- Initiated, architected and the main implementer of the Java agent new bytecode instrumentation. Replacing the original java bytecode instrumentation logic as part of the next phase of our java agent bytecode manipulation
- Replaced internal process to reduce ClassCircularityError issues
- Removed internal limitation for adding special instrumentations
- Worked on implementing several instrumentation features for our Java and .NET{CORE} instrumentation agents
- Enhanced method parameter reporting to be able to pinpoint which field within objects should be recorded
- Implemented and improved concurrency access to several internal structures used by our instrumentation agents
- Collaborated with the integration of Docker within our product and build process
- Created, documented and presented major implementations of our instrumentation agent product
- Mentored junior members of the group
- Interfaced with customers and solution engineers to resolve and improve the use of the product
- Converted the Classic Jenkins build process to Jenkins pipeline feature
- Used Java, C++, C#, Python, Groovy, git, Jenkins, Docker, Ant, Ivy, Maven, Archiva, Nexus and others to develop and support our instrumentation agents for Java and .NET{CORE}
- Worked with or extended our integration with Spring, JDBC, JMS, EJB, Axis, Netty, Vertx, WebSphere Application Server, Oracle WebLogic Application Server, Tomcat, Jetty, MongoDB and others

Technical Support Engineer

2011 - 2012

FUSE Source

Bedford, MA

- Responsible for the technical support, finding and fixing bugs for the ActiveMQ/Message Broker, ServiceMIX/ESB, Camel/Message Router and CXF/Service Framework products
- Created different patches for ActiveMQ, Camel, karaf and osp4j pax-logging projects that have been applied
- Helped customers on how to best use the product by giving advice and creating working examples that they can use as a starting point
- Developed a simple perl script that has helped improve our front-end services. This has allowed these systems to become stable when prior to this change these systems required constant attention
- Lead the bug queue process with engineering
- Part of the 24/7 support rotation for 24/7 production support for customers

Principal Software Engineer

May 2008 – July 2009

Progress Software Technology

- Primary developer for the ObjectStore[™]Java Middle Tier Library (JMTL), a highly scalable middle-tier caching & transaction management system. Responsibilities included design, implementation, scheduling, mentoring, testing, and documentation
 - * Updated JMTL integration with most prominent EJB servers such as Weblogic and JBoss using technologies such as JTA and XAResource
 - * Designed and implemented new features in JMTL such as real-time counter updates and run-time management tool
 - * Resolved major bugs within the JMTL update of JTA XAResource integration such as inconsistent committing/abort between ObjectStore transactions and application server XAResource transaction callbacks
 - * Assisted technical support concerning critical issues using ObjectStore™JMTL for customers such as NIST
- Contributing member of development team for ObjectStore, the leading Object-Oriented Database Management System
 - * Designed and implemented new feature in OSJI such that C++ real-time counter updates can be performed within OSJI java layer using JNI
 - * Updated endgame testing scripts such that OSJI 64-bit testing is properly setup and executed by the testing engineers

Principal Software Engineer

2007

Emptoris Burlington, MA

• Lead developer responsible for maintaining and enhancing Intelligence Attributes (IA) and IF Java-based frameworks used by other teams within the organization as a basis for several of Emptoris' commercial products

Senior Software Engineer

2000 - 2006

Progress Software Technology

Bedford, MA

- Primary developer for the ObjectStore[™]Java Middle Tier Library (JMTL), a highly scalable middle-tier caching & transaction management system. Responsibilities included design, implementation, scheduling, mentoring, testing, and documentation
 - * Integrated JMTL with most prominent EJB servers such as WebSphere, Weblogic, JBoss and Sun Application Server, using technologies such as JTS, JTA and XAResource
 - * Designed and implemented new features in JMTL such as object pooling mechanism, extent implementation, integration with two phase object locking mechanism, and its associated byte-code enhancement tool
 - * Created design documents in order to schedule and mentor other group members on implementation of feature enhancements such as two phase object locking byte-code enhancer tool and JMTL proxy code generator
 - * Enhanced existing features within JMTL such as the internal profiling feature, Console Swing tool, Virtual Transaction Manager, Virtual Transaction Manager Management tool
 - * Resolved major bugs within the JMTL transaction Manager such as inconsistent committing/abort between ObjectStore transactions and application server XA transactions
 - * Enhanced product build for JMTL by replacing makefiles with Ant build scripts
 - * Updated examples that ship with the product, such as EJB server examples, JMTL Servlet/JSP example for use with Tomcat and JMTL-specific Ant tasks
 - * Assisted consultants with issues concerning the usage and best practices using ObjectStore JMTL for customers such as Starwoods, Sakonnet, and Lockheed Martin
- Contributing member of development team for ObjectStore, the leading Object-Oriented Database Management System
 - * Contributed to development of a change-log mechanism for a Data Source Synchronization product (DSS) used to automatically synchronize data between ObjectStore and Oracle or MySQL
 - * Architected and designed testing process and framework using JUnit, then became go-to person to facilitate adoption of this framework within the ObjectStore Java group
 - * Contributed enhancements and performance improvements to the ObjectStore Java Interface (OSJI)

Developer Support Engineer

1998 - 2000

Progress Software Technology

Bedford, MA

- Responsible for technical support as well as finding and fixing bugs in ObjectStore & JMTL
- Trained and certified consulting group and support members on building and using purify with the ObjectStore product
- Mentored others on using non-ObjectStore tools such as Visual C++, ClearCase, snapshot system, debuggers, etc
- Worked on integration of our Java product with Sybase Jaguar EJB Server
- Obtained Sourcesmart certification on Solaris and WinNT
- Handled critical customers such as MarketXT, Fairmarket and Smith Barney, including emergent on-site troubleshooting

Consultant (assigned to First Data Corporation)

1998

CIBER Boston, MA

- * Server application used sockets, threads and MSSQL to process requests
- * Requests were to a mainframe, which were received from a Web application
- Implemented new API for the Web application to process requests to the mainframe

• Responsible for development on middle-tier of an application using C/C++ and Visual C++

- Enhanced application that retrieves data from the mainframe to populate an MSSQL database by replacing large and complex switch statements with a simple array of generic function pointers which streamlined their use of DLLs
- Added GUI feature for parsing data files to populate combo boxes
- Implemented support for seamless handling of Y2K and non-Y2K clients
- Responsible for fixing bugs uncovered by QA department, using Visual Source Safe for tracking changes
- Enhanced debugger tool used to check that implemented server API calls work properly

Consultant 1994-1998

Bell Sygma

Montreal, Quebec, Canada

- Developed an application to parse raw data from a DMS switch and store it in both a database and a shared memory cache so that GUI clients could make both real-time and historical queries against it. Included the following components:
 - * Back end interpreter of raw DMS data to be displayed at GUI client and stored in database
 - * IPC communication layer between GUI client and DMS data interpreter
 - * Client/server interface to generate embedded SQL queries using parameters specified via RPC
- Enhanced GUI client end of a real-time application by adding new features and making it internationally viable, using Neuron Data's Open Interface in C on UNIX
- Developed general library functions used throughout a real-time client/server application in C using object-oriented concepts
- Lead developer of back end program for intranet project, using C, embedded SQL and Ingres

Programmer 1994

Veritech

Montreal, Quebec, Canada

• Designed and implemented the preliminary structure of a video game using MFC/C++ on Windows

Programmer Analyst

1992 - 1994

Ranmar Business System

Montreal, Quebec, Canada

- Primary author of a GUI terminal emulation program using C and Windows SDK, which consisted of a protocol that dynamically generated client side windows based on properties specified on the server side
- Enhanced GUI library to support dynamic generation of windows
- Created new feature for financial and rating software package to allow users to view/edit client records, using C on UNIX

EDUCATION

Concordia University

Montreal, Quebec, Canada

Bachelor of Science, Specialization in Applied Mathematics, Minor in Computer Science

May 1992